JASON PUL FULLSTACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Summary

I'm an Air Force veteran that obtained a BS and MS in Mechanical Engineering after leaving the service. Following college, I worked in the Aerospace/Defense sector for many years. While working as an engineer, I really enjoyed creating software tools to increase productivity/efficiency. In fact I enjoyed it so much that I decided to pivot my career and attend a coding boot-camp to become a full-stack software engineer. Web applications are headed in a very exciting direction and I'm very interested in working with them to make modern applications. Both for the web and native environments. I have a passion for building things, both physically and through software. I'm a quick learner who is new to software engineering, but not to engineering.

Employment

Northrop Grumman

Survivability Engineer V

Melbourne, Florida June 2013 to Apr. 2020

Designed and Optimized Air Vehicle Components

- Designed Test Articles, Developed Test Requirements, and Supervised Test Article Builds
- Executed Tests, Post-processed Test Results, Produced Test Data Packages, and Presented Test Results to Internal and External Customers
- Lofted Computational ElectroMagnetic (CEM) Models, Meshed CEM Models, and Ran Model Predictions Utilizing High Performance Computers (HPCs)
- Developed Software Tools that Automated Tasks (model creation, data processing, etc) and Reduced Design and Analysis Cycle Times
- Lead a Team of 7 Engineers as a Component Lead
- Trained Jr Engineers in Both Theory and Tools Used in Survivability

Sandia National Laboratories

Member of Technical Staff - Structural Dynamics Analyst

Albuquerque, New Mexico Aug. 2011 to June 2013

- Produced Finite Element Models of Various Systems and Components
- Developed MATLAB Software that Ran LS-Dyna to Fit Simulations to Experimental Results
- Wrote MATLAB Scripts to Allow Production of Hundreds of LS-Dyna Analysis Decks Covering Desired Problem Space for Uncertainty Quantification
- Performed Implicit and Explicit Finite Element Simulations Utilizing High Performance Computers (HPCs)

Northrop Grumman

Engineer

El Segundo, California

- Performed Aerodynamic and Thermal Elastic Stress Analysis using Nastran
- Collaborated in Designing an Aero-Gel Thermal Conductivity Measurement Device
- Mechanical Lead in Design of Automated Web-Handling Material Qualification and Validation Apparatus
- Produced Vehicle Mesh Models Using CATIA & Patran
- Developed MATLAB Program Enabling Faster Post-Processing of Test Data

United States Air Force

Senior Airman, Enlisted

Wonju, Gangwon, South Korea Dec. 2003 to Nov. 2007

- Performed Spectral Analysis of Particulate Air Samples
- Deployed Worldwide to Set Up Portable Clean Rooms and Perform Anlaysis
- Maintained Seismic Array and Ensured Data Collections

Projects

JetOut July 2020 to Current

find the cheapest flights out of an airport without regard to destination

The Jiu Jitsu Guide Jan. 2020 to Current

TV Guide for streaming Brazilian Jiu Jitsu events

Scavenging Heroes
YouTube based game show

Jan. 2020 to Mar. 2020

Awards

Code Platoon · Best in Show July 2020

earned the top award for my personal project at coding boot camp

Activities

Brazilian Jiu Jitsu Fall 2008 to Current learning and practicing Brazilian Jiu Jitsu

Certifications

Contact

jasonpul.github.io/

5624405680

♀ Austin, Texas

in jason-pul/

(C) jasonpul

Education

Mt. San Antonio Community College Fall 2007 to Spring

University of Southern California

Fall 2008 to Spring 2010

BS Mechanical Engineering 2010

University of Southern California Spring 2010 to Fall 2011 MS Mechanical Engineering 2011

Skills

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Python

NumPy/SciPy

Django

JavaScript

Pandas

React PostgreSOL

SOI

PRODUCTIVITY/MISCELLANEOUS

Microsoft Office Suite

Torque I SF

Linux CLI

Matlah

SURVIVABILITY ENGINEER

SWITCH

GEMS

Ram2d SENTRi

Saher

MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

CATIA

Solidworks

Patran Nastran

LS-Dyna

LS-PrePost

Cubit

Hypermesh